<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[RSS Feed]]></title><description><![CDATA[OpenWeb]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 16:41:44 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Meta Lost $230 Billion Overnight. What Does That Mean For Publishers?]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>As dark as recent Facebook history has become, yesterday was a particularly bleak chapter. The stock of its parent company, Meta, fell by 26.4%, knocking $230 billion off its market value overnight.&nbsp; The cause? Most analysts agree it’s Apple—specifically, Apple&#8217;s new privacy policies, which allows iPhone users to opt-out of being tracked by the apps<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/meta-lost-230-billion-overnight-what-does-that-mean-for-publishers/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.commeta-lost-230-billion-overnight-what-does-that-mean-for-publishers</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.commeta-lost-230-billion-overnight-what-does-that-mean-for-publishers</guid><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 21:23:39 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;As dark as recent Facebook history has become, yesterday was a particularly bleak chapter. The stock of its parent company, Meta, fell by 26.4%, knocking $230 billion off its market value overnight.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cause? Most analysts agree it’s Apple—specifically, Apple&amp;#8217;s new privacy policies, which allows iPhone users to opt-out of being tracked by the apps they use. When Meta&amp;#8217;s CFO announced that those policies would cost the company $10 billion in sales in 2022, the stock began to tumble.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At the core of this story is something marketers have been fretting about for years: the end of the third-party cookie regime that has been the be-all-end-all of internet advertising for over a decade, and the fuel to the fire of Facebook’s historic growth. That coming reality has been discussed endlessly on marketing blogs, but as of yesterday, it&amp;#8217;s officially front-page news.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Between Apple&amp;#8217;s new policies and Google&amp;#8217;s looming cookie phase-out, the digital advertising ecosystem is going through its most significant upheaval in years (which, for an industry defined by upheaval, is saying something). Meta&amp;#8217;s decline—the biggest one-day retreat in US history—is just the most spectacular symptom of a change that affects thousands of companies all over the country.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;So: what&amp;#8217;s it all mean for publishers?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For the immediate future, third-party cookies certainly still have value. But publishers who fail to develop a game plan for the coming post-cookie world are setting themselves up for massive trouble down the line. And any post-cookie game plan would be incomplete without a focus on first-party data strategies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;First-party data—data collected directly from your readers, as they read and interact with your content—is just as effective as third-party data when it comes to targeting readers. It also happens to be less invasive, and much cheaper to acquire. And unlike third-party data, it&amp;#8217;s not going anywhere anytime soon.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;At OpenWeb, we believe the best route to first-party data is through building a community rooted in healthy conversation––the kinds of vibrant, non-toxic discussions that keep readers coming back. Active communities provide opportunities for better advertising experiences as third-party cookies fade away—and valuable first-party signals about what&amp;#8217;s working (and what isn&amp;#8217;t) that empower publishers to craft their content accordingly. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This is the basis of a content strategy that readers back more often, and acquiring still more first-party data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Best-in-class social experiences, re-engagement tools, and identity solutions help publishers build the kinds of communities they need in order to compete in the years ahead. Let Meta&amp;#8217;s very bad day be a warning: the post-cookie world is coming for us all. The best thing to do is plan ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Importance Of Dissenting Opinions In The Community]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s no secret that, on today&#8217;s internet, we&#8217;re siloed—stuck talking to people who agree with us already, usually about the blindness and/or idiocy of those unfortunate people trapped in the other silo. When leakage occurs––when someone from one silo ends up interacting with someone from a different silo—the result, more often than not, is catastrophic,<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/the-importance-of-dissenting-opinions-in-the-community/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.comthe-importance-of-dissenting-opinions-in-the-community</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.comthe-importance-of-dissenting-opinions-in-the-community</guid><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jan 2022 17:04:50 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s no secret that, on today&amp;#8217;s internet, we&amp;#8217;re siloed—stuck talking to people who agree with us already, usually about the blindness and/or idiocy of those unfortunate people trapped in the &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; silo. When leakage occurs––when someone from one silo ends up interacting with someone from a different silo—the result, more often than not, is catastrophic, at least on social media. Resident of Silo #1 tells Resident of Silo #2 that they&amp;#8217;re brainwashed; Resident of Silo #2 says that, actually, sorry, no, I believe &lt;em&gt;you&amp;#8217;re&lt;/em&gt; the one that&amp;#8217;s brainwashed. Then they start saying stuff we&amp;#8217;d rather not repeat. Things can get ugly at an astonishing speed.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, this is a genuine shame. No question, there&amp;#8217;s value in having one&amp;#8217;s viewpoint validated—back-patting is not a crime. But there is also real value in having your viewpoint tested. The benefits of good-faith back-and-forth are numerous. The problem is that, on much of the internet, good-faith debate is very nearly impossible to find.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As we now know, platforms like Facebook are expressly designed to stoke discord, highlighting the posts most likely to drive an extreme emotional reaction from users. Is there a way to preserve dissent online without inviting toxicity? The answer, we&amp;#8217;d argue, is yes. It just depends on good moderation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Why dissent matters&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Before delving into what moderation can do, it&amp;#8217;s worth expanding on some of the benefits of dissent. The fact is that when one side—any side—spends too much time talking to itself, it risks losing touch with the outside world. Assumptions go unquestioned, and groupthink takes hold. Dissent—whether from members of the community itself, or from members of entirely different communities—can help counteract some of these negative tendencies. It can help people realize flaws or blindspots in their arguments, or open their eyes to dimensions of the issue they might not have even thought about.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;More to the point: without dissent, things get boring. When you can instantly guess your community&amp;#8217;s reaction to this or that news story; when you hear the same trite remarks, day in and day out; when it feels like everything&amp;#8217;s &lt;em&gt;settled&lt;/em&gt;, and the task of each day is to repeat and strengthen what you already believe&amp;#8230; well, that&amp;#8217;s when dissent can make a real difference. Dissent, contrary to its negative associations, can actually keep things interesting.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of course, the world we&amp;#8217;re describing here—in which people with clashing views work jointly towards some version of truth, or at least argue without resorting to caps-lock—depends on good-faith engagement. A vast gulf exists between respectful disagreement and ad-hominem insult-trading.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There are people online who really do want to talk things out, but too often they&amp;#8217;re overshadowed by the “bad eggs”—that small but influential subset of people online whose main interest is sowing chaos. &lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt; is where moderation can really make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Moderation can keep things interesting—and safe&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenWeb&amp;#8217;s moderation tools help to keep discourse civil. Our AI/ML-powered tech discerns the content of each comment before it&amp;#8217;s posted—it can detect incivility levels, author attacks, spam/abuse, and more. Our tools also track behavior on the user level, allowing us to deemphasize the contributions of users with a history of derailing the conversation. Respectful contributions, meanwhile, are spotlighted, setting the tone for the larger conversation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;That conversation, depending on the subject, might be light-hearted; it might be serious, funny, intense. There may be real disagreements—on the merits of a politician, a pot roast recipe, a streaming show—and these disagreements might lead to lengthy debate. And that, we believe, is a very good thing. It&amp;#8217;s part of the fun of being online. The goal—wholly achievable through OpenWeb&amp;#8217;s technology—is to foster that spirit of debate without letting it lapse into toxicity. You want to keep things safe for everyone involved, without stifling the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The community plays a role in keeping things safe, too: OpenWeb offers users easy ways to flag comments that they feel are out of line, empowering them to police the boundaries of their own communities. When enough people have flagged a comment, OpenWeb&amp;#8217;s human moderation—operational 24/7, 365 days a year—will promptly take a closer look.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;A vibrant community can make a major difference&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The kinds of conversation that all this moderation facilitates can create significant value for publishers. Lively conversation keeps users coming back: they come to know and like regular commenters, and become regular commenters themselves. That means more return visits, more time-on-site, more registrations, and more paid subscriptions. It means more loyalty to your brand and content, and to the community thriving around both. And it means more first-party data, which you can use to more precisely target your readership. (It goes without saying that, with the imminent demise of third-party cookies, first-party data is more important than ever.)&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With users growing more and more sick of the pointless strife on social media, publishers have an excellent chance to position themselves as an alternative—a place where people can engage in friendly debate without insulting or doxxing one another. In an environment like that, even the most hardened troll just might find themselves contributing something useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Preventing Node-Sass (Or Any Specific Dependency) From Installing]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>If you’re using sass&nbsp;in your frontend projects (which we definitely recommend!), you’ve probably run into node-sass&nbsp;in one way or another.&nbsp;Node-sass is a C++ add on for NodeJS that binds libsass, the C language compiler for the sass language. Both node-sass&nbsp;and&nbsp;libsass&nbsp;have been&nbsp;deprecated&nbsp;in favor of Dart Sass (sass) since October 2020. While they were built to be<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/preventing-node-sass-or-any-specific-dependency-from-installing/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.compreventing-node-sass-or-any-specific-dependency-from-installing</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.compreventing-node-sass-or-any-specific-dependency-from-installing</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 05:48:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;If you’re using sass&amp;nbsp;in your frontend projects (which we definitely recommend!), you’ve probably run into node-sass&amp;nbsp;in one way or another.&amp;nbsp;Node-sass is a C++ add on for NodeJS that binds libsass, the C language compiler for the sass language. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Both node-sass&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;libsass&amp;nbsp;have been&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sass-lang.com/blog/libsass-is-deprecated&quot;&gt;deprecated&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;in favor of Dart Sass (sass) since October 2020. While they were built to be fast, they have the disadvantage of long build times, and breaking unexpectedly when using a new NodeJS version—or missing any required tooling for building the dependencies.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the end of 2021 (and after many such issues over the years), the OpenWeb team ran into a problem preventing us from building most frontend projects due to a platform change that removed one of the dependencies used by the&amp;nbsp;node-sass&amp;nbsp;build process. In most cases, we were migrated to&amp;nbsp;sass, but multiple dependencies were still referencing&amp;nbsp;node-sass —meaning that it was being installed and compiled, but not used.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;We Were Faced With Two Choices&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Update all nested dependencies to use sass and update all projects to use the new versions of said dependencies, or&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find a way to prevent node-sass from being installed downstream even if referenced by a dependency.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Normally, if you want to prevent something from being used, you can use&amp;nbsp;null-loader&amp;nbsp;(on Webpack 4), or disable the dependency using an&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/webpack-contrib/null-loader&quot;&gt;alias&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(on Webpack 5), but this will not prevent the dependency from being installed and built—only from being included in your built asset.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Since we use&amp;nbsp;yarn&amp;nbsp;1 (npm&amp;nbsp;and&amp;nbsp;yarn&amp;nbsp;2 instructions included below) as our package manager, a good place to start looking was&amp;nbsp;yarns&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&quot;https://classic.yarnpkg.com/lang/en/docs/selective-version-resolutions/&quot;&gt;resolutions&lt;/a&gt; section, which allows resolving multiple versions of a dependency to one version.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The issue here was that&amp;nbsp;resolutions&amp;nbsp;allows us to specify a specific version, but not disable the dependency entirely as in Webpack 5. The&amp;nbsp;yarn&amp;nbsp;documentation also specifies that you can use a local file in the&amp;nbsp;dependency&amp;nbsp;section (file:&amp;#8230;) but does not specify the same for&amp;nbsp;resolutions. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;This meant that going by the documentation, you could redirect a downstream dependency to a local file, but not anything used by upstream dependencies. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, we tried specifying a local stub dependency for&amp;nbsp;node-sass&amp;nbsp;to try to prevent it from installing the actual dependency, and it worked with&amp;nbsp;resolutions&amp;nbsp;as well! Now we could easily redirect&amp;nbsp;node-sass&amp;nbsp;to a stub, prevent it from being installed without updating any dependencies, and solve the issue rather quickly.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Our Step-By-Step Solution&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;Install&amp;nbsp;sass&amp;nbsp;using&amp;nbsp;yarn add -D sass&amp;nbsp;if not installed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Create a folder named&amp;nbsp;dependency-stub&amp;nbsp;in the project root, housing a single file named&amp;nbsp;index.js&amp;nbsp;containing the line&amp;nbsp;module.exports = {};&amp;nbsp;(which is the stub we will redirect to using&amp;nbsp;resolutions).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;yarn&amp;nbsp;2 &amp;#8211; add a&amp;nbsp;package.json&amp;nbsp;file to the directory containing&amp;nbsp;{ &amp;#8220;name: &amp;#8220;node-sass&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;version&amp;#8221;: &amp;#8220;0.0.0&amp;#8221; }&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;npm&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8211; see note under step 3.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ol start=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;In&amp;nbsp;package.json&amp;nbsp;add&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;node-sass&amp;#8221;: &amp;#8220;file:dependency-stub&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;to the&amp;nbsp;resolutions&amp;nbsp;(or&amp;nbsp;overrides&amp;nbsp;if using NPM) section.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;npm&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8211; use the&amp;nbsp;overrides&amp;nbsp;section rather than&amp;nbsp;resolutions, and since&amp;nbsp;npm&amp;nbsp;file urls are relative to the current dependency, you can either use an absolute path to&amp;nbsp;dependency-stub&amp;nbsp;(possibly placing it in your home directory), a URL for a stub module, or a GitHub URL for a stub module.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;ol start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&lt;li&gt;In&amp;nbsp;tsconfig.json&amp;nbsp;add&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8220;dependency-stub&amp;#8221;&amp;nbsp;to the&amp;nbsp;include&amp;nbsp;array (to prevent ESLint from throwing errors regarding the file not being in the project).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;npm&amp;nbsp;&amp;#8211; assuming&amp;nbsp;dependency-stub&amp;nbsp;isn’t in your project directory, this is not needed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;(Step 3 of the process can be reused for any arbitrary C++ NodeJS add on, assuming it isn’t used).&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And that was it! node-sass&amp;nbsp;stopped installing in all projects and the issue was resolved (save for a few projects with out of date&amp;nbsp;sass-loaders&amp;nbsp;which needed manual updating). Hopefully, this will help anyone else needing to quickly remove&amp;nbsp;node-sass.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[OpenWeb Builds on Commitment to Empowering Publishers Through Tech; Acquires Hive Media]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Back in November we announced our Series E funding round. At that time we talked about how the new investment would be used to build more, better tools for publishers to create direct relationships with their audiences and to improve online conversation. Today, we&#8217;re delighted to announce that we&#8217;ve acquired Hive Media—a leading expert in<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/openweb-builds-on-commitment-to-empowering-publishers-through-tech-acquires-hive-media/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.comopenweb-builds-on-commitment-to-empowering-publishers-through-tech-acquires-hive-media</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.comopenweb-builds-on-commitment-to-empowering-publishers-through-tech-acquires-hive-media</guid><pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 01:47:46 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;Back in November we announced our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.axios.com/nytimes-openweb-tech-unicorn-0a55d6ae-79e5-43f9-a050-55fe2f1b3ffc.html&quot;&gt;Series E funding round&lt;/a&gt;. At that time we talked about how the new investment would be used to build more, better tools for publishers to create direct relationships with their audiences and to improve online conversation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Today, we&amp;#8217;re delighted to announce that we&amp;#8217;ve acquired Hive Media—a leading expert in publisher technology. Onboarding their incredible expertise is a major step toward enhancing our tools and empowering publishers.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With Hive&amp;#8217;s technology, we&amp;#8217;ll expand our ability to build and test innovative tools that power first-party data-driven audience relationships, building impactful editorial tools, and increasing the long term value for publishers. Hive’s team brings best-in-class expertise in session optimization, user acquisition, and SEO tools—and we couldn&amp;#8217;t be more excited.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bringing Hive Media into the OpenWeb family propels our growth, adding more than 60 new team members, primarily across product and engineering. Additionally, Guy Yeshua and Stacy Aabraham will remain as Chief Executive Officer and Chief Operating Officer, respectively, of Hive, with Yeshua joining our executive leadership team. This means that OpenWeb’s global team is now more than 225 across its offices in New York, Tel Aviv, Kiev, and California.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenWeb and Hive Media have long been close strategic allies, and share a purpose: to empower publishers to be successful. Together, we will  move closer to fulfilling our mission to save online conversation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you’re a publisher working with us, or with Hive Media, and have any questions at all please reach out to your main point of contact. We&amp;#8217;d love to chat and explore further opportunities. If you&amp;#8217;re not working with us yet, it&amp;#8217;s great time to start—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/contact/&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Meet Peyton Marcus, OpenWeb’s New COO]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>We’re excited to announce that Peyton Marcus has joined OpenWeb to take over the role of Chief Operating Officer. She’s going to be instrumental in helping us continue to drive our mission and business forward.&nbsp; Peyton will be part of the executive leadership team and report directly to Nadav Shoval, our co-founder and CEO. She<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/meet-peyton-marcus-openwebs-new-coo/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.commeet-peyton-marcus-openwebs-new-coo</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.commeet-peyton-marcus-openwebs-new-coo</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 15:13:09 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;We’re excited to announce that Peyton Marcus has joined OpenWeb to take over the role of Chief Operating Officer. She’s going to be instrumental in helping us continue to drive our mission and business forward.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Peyton will be part of the executive leadership team and report directly to Nadav Shoval, our co-founder and CEO. She will be responsible for crucial projects that are underway for 2022 and beyond, including OpenWeb’s continued global expansion, innovation, and team growth. She brings unique leadership experience, an invaluable skill set in scaling operations across verticals in the media industry, and has a true passion for our mission to save online conversation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To paraphrase something Peyton recently said, we are at a point in history where the conversations we have online are shaping real societal outcomes, making OpenWeb’s work absolutely critical. Now is the time for us to use the momentum we’ve built to elevate our reach and capabilities, and really make an impact. Peyton will play an incredibly important role in supporting and challenging the team as we evolve our business to further accelerate that rapid growth.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Roee Goldberg, our wonderful co-founder who served as the COO over the past seven years, will maintain his position on the executive leadership team with a focus on company growth initiatives, including mergers and acquisitions, and expansion to new verticals.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Peyton comes to OpenWeb from a4, the advertising division of Altice USA, a cable television company, where she served as Senior Vice President (SVP), Revenue Operations, and before that, Cheddar, where she was SVP, Operations.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;To learn more, read the press release &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/openweb-appoints-peyton-marcus-as-chief-operating-officer-301460245.html?tc=eml_cleartime&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Publishers Need Engaged Communities—But They Can Only Grow With The Right Moderation Tools]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The free-for-all model of online conversation has had its chance and failed; we now know, all too well, what happens when an online forum is left to its own devices. We also know, via the Facebook Papers (and our own lived experiences), what happens when the most inflammatory elements of a conversation are intentionally elevated–chaos<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/publishers-need-engaged-communities-and-the-right-moderation-tools/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.compublishers-need-engaged-communities-and-the-right-moderation-tools</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.compublishers-need-engaged-communities-and-the-right-moderation-tools</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 20:48:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;The free-for-all model of online conversation has had its chance and failed; we now know, all too well, what happens when an online forum is left to its own devices. We also know, via the Facebook Papers (and our own lived experiences), what happens when the most inflammatory elements of a conversation are intentionally elevated–chaos reigns, pointless arguments and personal attacks grow and spread like weeds. A new year offers a new chance to clear those weeds away, opening space for smart discourse to bloom.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For publishers, that means opening up the comments sections––those much-maligned town squares in which anyone can have their say, whatever that may be. At OpenWeb, it&amp;#8217;s our sincere belief that a comments section can be a space of pure possibility––a place where like-minded readers can connect, swap jokes and stories, and generally increase the world&amp;#8217;s quotient of happiness and fellow-feeling.&amp;nbsp; A comments section can also help publishers calculate a variety of important metrics, like traffic per article, time users spend on each page, and more.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Having a successful comment section that’s both engaging for readers and useful for publishers, however, is dependent on the behavior of all involved. If aggression and toxicity reign, no one is going to get anything out of it. In today’s climate, that’s a very real concern for publishers.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;So how can publishers get to that ideal of free and easy intelligent public discourse? Quality, multi-layered moderation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Why Moderation Matters For Publishers&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Sane, respectful dialogue is its own reward. But it can also, for publishers, yield countless competitive advantages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In 2022, we&amp;#8217;ll likely see a continued move away from the traditional Web 2.0 publishing model––i.e., mostly free content disseminated at scale via social media. Publishers are more wary than ever of social media (and with good reason), while readers, primed by streaming services and subscription boxes, are more willing than ever to pay for quality content. Accordingly, paywalls have proliferated, and subscriptions are making up an ever-larger share of publishers&amp;#8217; revenues.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In this arena, an engaged, toxicity-free comments section can play a major role. It offers a sense of community, and turns what could otherwise be a passive reading experience into an engaged, two-way dialogue. Nothing is likelier to keep the reader coming back—and the more return visits a reader makes, the likelier that reader is to subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s a process of turning casual readers into loyal, logged-in users. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/openwebos/identity/&quot;&gt;OpenWebOS Identity&lt;/a&gt; helps to make this happen, incentivizing registrations and boosting revenue, retention, session duration, and pageviews. In 2022, the clock is audibly counting down on third-party cookies, which makes the first-party data you can get from registered users more valuable than ever.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Everyone&lt;/em&gt; Is Tired of Fighting&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In the years (!) since the pandemic started, countless facets of US life have been revealed as, basically, hollow traditions—things we did because we never stopped to think about why we were doing them. Obviously, phenomena like the Great Resignation come to mind—people fed up, finally, with thankless, unremunerative work. But the furor around the Facebook Papers suggests that people are also sick of online toxicity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Nearly two decades into Web 2.0, the thought of witnessing (let alone participating in) another flame war, pile-on, or name-calling tournament is enough to chuck one&amp;#8217;s devices into the sea. How much longer can we go on like this? Why are we going on like this in the first place?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;By turning their websites into oases in the deafening storm of noise, publishers can capitalize on this pervasive sense of burnout. With the right moderation tools, what had once seemed like a fantasy—polite, intelligent conversation, on the &lt;em&gt;internet&lt;/em&gt; of all places-––becomes eminently achievable. Offer that, and you&amp;#8217;re sure to have a banner year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Moderation: The Most Effective Tool in the Fight Against Toxicity&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/openwebos/moderation/&quot;&gt;OpenWebOS&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8216; advanced moderation tools are designed to foster a new kind of online conversation—one that&amp;#8217;s insightful, engaged, and decidedly non-toxic. Every posted comment is intensively vetted via AI and machine learning tools, which are able to identify incivility levels, white supremacy, spam/abuse, and more. Behavior is tracked at the user level, so repeat offenders are de-emphasized; intelligent contributions, meanwhile, are floated to the top, setting the tone for civilized, engaged discourse.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Partisan energies in America show no sign of slowing down: 2022 is, after all, an election year, and we can expect the discourse&amp;#8217;s temperature to rise considerably as we get closer to the midterms. No one can eliminate partisan rancor from American life––but, by the same token, no one should have to host it on their website. &lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Hard as it is to believe, there are still people––tons of them––who may disagree with each other but who are still willing to discuss these disagreements civilly. Common ground can still be found. With the right moderation tools, publishers can ensure that their websites become spaces for productive, exciting conversations.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Where We’ve Been, Where We’re Going: Notes on 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>The end of the year is an occasion for champagne, novelty glasses, and healthy self-reflection. And if you don&#8217;t mind, we&#8217;d like to indulge in a little bit of that last thing ourselves. Because the fact is that this has been, for us at OpenWeb, a banner year—among the most exciting in our company&#8217;s nearly<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/where-weve-been-where-were-going-notes-on-2021/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.comwhere-weve-been-where-were-going-notes-on-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.comwhere-weve-been-where-were-going-notes-on-2021</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 20:40:28 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;The end of the year is an occasion for champagne, novelty glasses, and healthy self-reflection. And if you don&amp;#8217;t mind, we&amp;#8217;d like to indulge in a little bit of that last thing ourselves. Because the fact is that this has been, for us at OpenWeb, a banner year—among the most exciting in our company&amp;#8217;s nearly decade-long history. Barely a day passed without &lt;em&gt;something&lt;/em&gt; notable happening: a new feature, a new initiative, a new financial milestone. So join us, below, as we walk through some of OpenWeb&amp;#8217;s 2021 highlights.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Remarkable Outcomes For Publishers&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A leading theme this year? The incredible results we generated in our partnerships, supporting the bottom-line outcomes that matter most to the publishing industry.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Among users registered with OpenWeb across our publishing network, we saw:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-large&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;560&quot; src=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/uploads/2021/12/Mail-560x560px-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;wp-image-9785&quot; srcset=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/uploads/2021/12/Mail-560x560px-2.jpg 560w, https://www.openweb.com/uploads/2021/12/Mail-560x560px-2-150x150@2x.jpg 300w, https://www.openweb.com/uploads/2021/12/Mail-560x560px-2-150x150.jpg 150w&quot; sizes=&quot;(max-width: 560px) 100vw, 560px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;OpenWeb Becomes Tech&amp;#8217;s Newest Unicorn&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of course, we can&amp;#8217;t &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; mention this year&amp;#8217;s biggest milestone: the $150 million in Series E funding that turned OpenWeb into tech&amp;#8217;s latest &amp;#8220;unicorn,&amp;#8221; with a valuation of over $1B. Some big names made this round possible: prestigious investors like Insight Partners and Georgian, industry luminaries like the New York Times Company, Professor Scott Galloway (who also joined our board), Samsung Next, and more. That the news was trumpeted on the Times Square NASDAQ billboard was just the icing on the cake.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The round was a loud vote of confidence in OpenWeb&amp;#8217;s central mission: the creation of a safer alternative to existing social media platforms, one that empowers publishers and brands across verticals with tools to build vibrant communities (and first-party data relationships with their audiences).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;We Started Some Amazing New Partnerships&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As this year&amp;#8217;s many “big tech” scandals demonstrated, these efforts are more essential than ever. At OpenWeb, we&amp;#8217;re proud to play a role in what comes next for media. This year, we welcomed to our roster such distinguished publishers as Yahoo, Forbes, the Wall Street Journal, The New York Post, and more. They entered our network which, in 2021, has a safety score of 99.1%. With this latest funding round, we&amp;#8217;ll be maintaining and improving on those already-high standards, while innovating across our product to power the web.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;What Else Did We Get Up to in 2021?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Speaking of product innovation… We were busy this year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Take &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/influencing-quality-with-the-best-sorting-algorithm&quot;&gt;Best Sorting&lt;/a&gt;: the feature that surfaces and prioritizes the highest-quality comments, thereby decreasing exposure to lower-quality, more toxic comments and elevating the overall discourse. Or take &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/reactions-get-a-pulse-on-your-community-with-interactive-polls&quot;&gt;Reactions&lt;/a&gt;, which lets users engage with content in a more direct way (and lets publishers monetize that interaction). Or look at the enhancements we made to a number of our pre-existing offerings, like our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/openwebos/moderation/&quot;&gt;Conversation moderation technology&lt;/a&gt;. We introduced &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/openwebos/experience/&quot;&gt;Topic Tracker&lt;/a&gt;, which lets users receive notifications on specific subjects of interest, and vastly improved our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/release-notes/&quot;&gt;onsite Notifications capabilities&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, furthering our commitment to reducing toxicity online, we engaged in first-of-their-kind cross-industry partnerships with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/were-partnering-with-newsguard-to-combat-misinformation/&quot;&gt;NewsGuard&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/were-making-strides-against-toxicity-and-disinformation-online-in-partnership-with-the-global-disinformation-index-heres-how/&quot;&gt;Global Disinformation Index&lt;/a&gt;. With their help, each publisher in our network is now &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/an-inside-look-at-how-were-working-to-facilitate-healthier-online-environments/&quot;&gt;audited on a quarterly basis&lt;/a&gt;; if both NewsGuard and GDI identify a publisher as less-than-credible, we initiate an investigation. These partnerships are a testament to how seriously we take our mission to improve online conversations—how committed we are to creating a healthy informational ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;New Team Members, New Offices&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Of course, none of this would be possible without our team, which also grew significantly this year: overall, we made over 50 hires in engineering, IT, business development, data, marketing, and partner success. We added experienced leaders, expanded our board of directors, and opened an R&amp;amp;D hub in Kyiv.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And, most importantly, we produced tangible results for publishers: in 2021, users registered through OpenWeb showed 79% additional daily time-on-site, 45% uplift in time-on-page, and a 23% increase in page views.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Looking Ahead to 2022&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Perhaps this is cliché, but it’s true: We’re just getting started.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Looking towards 2022, we plan to seriously scale our operations: more team members in more countries working to improve our discourse and help publishers grow.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, our mission extends far beyond your laptop or cell phone screen—because as we all know by now, you can&amp;#8217;t separate the digital realm from real life. What happens in one has an impact on the other, for better or for worse. A safer, kinder internet—anchored by a free, diverse, and financially healthy publisher ecosystem—makes for a safer, kinder world. At OpenWeb, that&amp;#8217;s the world we&amp;#8217;ve been building towards. And we plan to keep building towards it, in 2022 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Publishers Should Feel Optimistic About 2022]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Optimism, these days, is a tough thing to sustain. It&#8217;s tough for everyone, but it&#8217;s especially tough for publishers, whose business model Big Tech continues to chip away at. But a new year is almost upon us, and with it a chance to rethink old approaches. The fact is that, despite the doomsaying, this is<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/why-publishers-should-feel-optimistic-about-2022/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.comwhy-publishers-should-feel-optimistic-about-2022</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.comwhy-publishers-should-feel-optimistic-about-2022</guid><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 16:54:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;Optimism, these days, is a tough thing to sustain. It&amp;#8217;s tough for everyone, but it&amp;#8217;s especially tough for publishers, whose business model Big Tech continues to chip away at. But a new year is almost upon us, and with it a chance to rethink old approaches.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The fact is that, despite the doomsaying, this is actually an excellent time to be a publisher. In an uncertain world, where we&amp;#8217;re always on the brink of the next COVID variant or political meltdown (or so it feels), people are desperate to be informed. They are also desperate for community. The big social companies have shown themselves unequipped (or unwilling) to foster the kind of illuminating, non-toxic discussions that people crave. By allowing their platforms to devolve into chaos, they&amp;#8217;ve created a real need for connection that publishers are perfectly positioned to fill.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Which is all to say that publishers really do have a lot to feel optimistic about, as we enter 2022. With OpenWeb&amp;#8217;s technology, they can capitalize on the widespread desire for connection, and in the process drastically boost retention and revenue. Below, a quick guide to some of the ways that OpenWeb helps publishers to build flourishing, hate-free communities.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Bringing Your Readers Together&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Commenters have long gotten a bad rap—disparaged as trolls or troublemakers, caricatured on sitcoms as mouth-breathing nerds. These notions are, obviously, absurd. All kinds of people leave comments. Some—a glancingly small minority—do so with the intention of sowing chaos or hate. But the vast majority of commenters are posting in good faith. These are people who want to extend the conversation that your content has started—people with fresh, enriching perspectives, relevant anecdotes, solid jokes. The trick is to amplify their contributions while minimizing (or, if they&amp;#8217;ve broken the rules, deleting) the kinds of comments that throw a wrench in the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenWebOS was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/openwebos/moderation/&quot;&gt;designed to do precisely that&lt;/a&gt;. Every posted comment is put through a multi-pronged moderation process to ensure that quality is prioritized. Think of one of those airport x-ray systems—each comment sent down the conveyor belt, inspected for incivility, white supremacy, spam/abuse, etc. Our technology also takes into account the individual poster&amp;#8217;s history—building Civility Profiles on each commenter and using them to evaluate each new comment. In other words: a trollish comment, from someone with a history of trollish comments, will be automatically deprioritized. Meanwhile, through Best Sorting, the highest-quality contributions will be floated to the top. The end result is a smarter, saner, and decidedly less toxic discourse.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Comments as the Ultimate Retention Tool&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Picture a cafe overrun with volatile loudmouths. They&amp;#8217;re harassing the barista, spray painting the walls, interrupting pleasant conversations. Now picture a placid, sun-filled cafe where, at different tables, people engage in polite, overlapping dialogues. Where would &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; rather spend more time?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Put otherwise: when a reader reaches the bottom of an article and finds a festering swamp of invective and hate, that reader&amp;#8217;s going to promptly close the tab. Stimulating discourse, on the other hand, is a surefire route to retention. Your website becomes a place that people want to return to, over and over again—to read your content, of course, but also to see what your community has to say about it.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And in the new internet economy that&amp;#8217;s currently taking shape, retention is first priority. 2022 brings us ever-closer to an online marketing ecosystem primarily reliant on first-party data, and the more time your users spend on-site, the more first-party data they&amp;#8217;ll generate. A healthy community redounds to the benefit not just of commenters, but of all readers, even those too shy to comment. From a retention perspective, lurkers are just as useful as posters—and people are much more likely to lurk if the conversation is respectful, fun, vibrant.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Liveblogs, Topic Tracking, Polls, and More&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Beyond comments, OpenWeb offers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/openwebos/experience/&quot;&gt;countless ways&lt;/a&gt; to boost retention (and, consequently, revenue). Our technology makes liveblogging easy—editors can guide readers through major cultural events in real-time, and even take questions from the audience. WIth OpenWeb&amp;#8217;s Topic Tracker, readers can follow and receive notifications about the topics they care about the most, encouraging them to register, stay longer, and keep coming back. Real-time polls, meanwhile, are another rich resource—a way to keep readers engaged while soliciting valuable feedback and first-party data.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;2022: A New Beginning&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;For publishers, these are exciting times: people are more eager than ever to engage online, but warier than ever of doing so on traditional social media platforms, where the loudest and most toxic voices are given free rein to wreck the discourse. OpenWeb&amp;#8217;s moderation and engagement tools allow publishers to turn their own websites into thriving communities—healthy, fun alternatives to the chaos of social media. As the &amp;#8217;20s kick off in earnest—let&amp;#8217;s call the COVID era a false start—it&amp;#8217;s time to reassess the effort we&amp;#8217;re putting into the big social platforms, and build something new.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[2021: A Year In Conversations]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Conversation is the social glue that binds us together — and in another year when many of us had to remain physically apart, a huge proportion of that conversation took place online.&nbsp; OpenWeb was there to track the ups and downs of online conversation throughout 2021, from the bitter aftermath of the Presidential election to<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/2021-a-year-in-conversations/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.com2021-a-year-in-conversations</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.com2021-a-year-in-conversations</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 14:59:17 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;Conversation is the social glue that binds us together — and in another year when many of us had to remain physically apart, a huge proportion of that conversation took place online.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;OpenWeb was there to track the ups and downs of online conversation throughout 2021, from the bitter aftermath of the Presidential election to the uplifting return of major sporting events. Through it all, we provided advice for publishers on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/openwebos/experience/&quot;&gt;building loyal and engaged communities&lt;/a&gt; by elevating the quality of online debate. Here’s our month-by-month summary of our top blogs from 2021.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Capitol riots underscore the need for healthier online discourse&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The world watched in shock in January as supporters of ex-President Trump stormed the Capitol building following his election defeat. Many blamed social media platforms for promoting toxic comments that led to real-world violence. We suggested &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/why-quality-is-key-in-the-aftermath-of-the-capitol-attacks/&quot;&gt;a better way to encourage online debate&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;War of words leads to Facebook news ban Down Under&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;In February, an escalating battle over revenues led to a showdown between Australian publishers and social platforms — resulting in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/publishers-facebook-is-not-your-friend/&quot;&gt;sudden Facebook ban for news outlets&lt;/a&gt;. It was a wake-up call for publishers to start building 1:1 relationships with readers, rather than ceding control to third parties.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Learning from the world’s most disastrous experiment in content moderation&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;What happens when you let people argue anonymously online with no moderation? Those arguments soon become toxic and hate-filled, debasing the quality of online discourse. In May we looked at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/learning-from-the-most-disastrous-experiment-in-moderation&quot;&gt;what publishers can learn from the fate of Parler&lt;/a&gt;, the short-lived “free speech” platform.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Google rows back on cookie deprecation — but publishers should act anyway&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Having rattled advertisers in March, in June Google &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/google-delays-the-death-of-third-party-cookies-what-this-means-for-publishers&quot;&gt;postponed its deprecation date for third-party cookies&lt;/a&gt; by a year, to 2023. But the end is still in sight, and publishers who act now to build a solid first-party data strategy stand to reap the benefits. We looked at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/is-loyalty-the-new-1st-party-data&quot;&gt;how reader comments can help with that&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;The return of the Summer Olympics — and new opportunities for publishers&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;After the cancellations and disappointments of 2020, the rescheduled Tokyo Summer Olympics was cause for celebration in July. Sports fans looked to online news sites for live coverage of key events, creating superb opportunities for publishers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/stadiums-will-be-empty-in-tokyo-but-you-can-still-build-an-audience-around-the-olympics&quot;&gt;engage audiences in quality conversation&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;OpenWeb and the Global Disinformation Index team up to combat toxic conversations&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to create healthy spaces for online debate, but we can only do that by working with publishers who share our values. We took a vital step in August by partnering with the Global Disinformation Index to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/were-making-strides-against-toxicity-and-disinformation-online-in-partnership-with-the-global-disinformation-index-heres-how&quot;&gt;update our publisher standards&lt;/a&gt; (and stop working with domains that don’t meet them).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;PSL, NFL, and a time for publishers to strengthen audience relationships&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;September heralded the return of some of our favorite things, like the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/what-can-we-learn-from-pumpkin-spice&quot;&gt;aroma of pumpkin-spiced lattes&lt;/a&gt; and the excitement of a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/how-sports-publishers-can-build-audience-engagement-during-the-nfl-season&quot;&gt;new football season&lt;/a&gt;. They may seem very different, but they both get people talking—and hosting those online conversations is a win-win for publishers and audiences.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Facebook’s bad week shines a spotlight on online toxicity&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The world’s biggest social platform was in trouble (again) in October. In the same week Facebook experienced two major outages, whistleblower Frances Haugen appeared on &lt;em&gt;60 Minutes&lt;/em&gt; to expose the way the company uses toxicity to drive “engagement”. Once again, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/what-facebooks-bad-week-means-for-publishers&quot;&gt;we proposed a better way&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator&quot;/&gt;



&lt;p class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;What will 2022 bring to the conversation?&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;With 2021 nearly over, we look forward to sharing many more highs and lows from the world of online conversation in 2022. If you’d like to learn more about how we help publishers to build and engage audiences — and find new revenue streams — by hosting quality online conversations, you can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/&quot;&gt;browse more insights on the OpenWeb blog&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/contact/&quot;&gt;contact us directly here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Brands That Have Nailed the Art of Online Community Building]]></title><description><![CDATA[<p>Communities have been forming on the internet for as long as the internet has been a thing, showing just how strong the human urge is to find and bond with like-minded people.&nbsp; And while some online communities (especially those with poor moderation) become rife with toxicity, others become beacons of social cohesion: offering a place<a class="moretag" href="https://wordpress.openweb.com/brands-that-have-nailed-the-art-of-online-community-building/">Read More</a></p>
]]></description><link>https://www.openweb.combrands-that-have-nailed-the-art-of-online-community-building</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.openweb.combrands-that-have-nailed-the-art-of-online-community-building</guid><pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2021 17:32:32 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>
&lt;p&gt;Communities have been forming on the internet for as long as the internet has been a thing, showing just how strong the human urge is to find and bond with like-minded people.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;And while some online communities (especially &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/learning-from-the-most-disastrous-experiment-in-moderation&quot;&gt;those with poor moderation&lt;/a&gt;) become rife with toxicity, others become beacons of social cohesion: offering a place where people can go to find support, advice, and a sense of belonging.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Many of the communities in that second category are hosted by brands who know the value of cultivating quality conversations around their products. There’s a lot that publishers can learn from these brands about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/the-benefits-of-building-a-community-around-your-brand/&quot;&gt;leveraging the power of the community&lt;/a&gt; — whether it’s to increase reach, build reputation, optimize customer service, or source new ideas.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Here are five brands we think have nailed the art of creating an online community.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Glossier: Making space for quality conversation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The online beauty brand started out as a blog, later pivoting its readership into an engaged global customer base for its beauty products. By selling direct to consumers rather than through marketplaces, Glossier has developed close relationships with its community of fans, who it looks to for feedback on existing products and ideas for new ones.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Glossier has &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.femalefoundersfund.com/glossier-president-cfo-henry-davis-on-building-a-passionate-community-1e407eaeed13&quot;&gt;four principles for building a strong online community&lt;/a&gt;, including “make space for conversation” and “make the consumer feel seen”. Publishers can adopt both of these tactics to engage audiences and cultivate loyalty. A &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/the-comments-is-more-valuable-than-you-think&quot;&gt;well-moderated comments section&lt;/a&gt; is an ideal space for quality conversation, and giving kudos to commenters who make valued contributions to that conversation is a great way to make readers feel seen and appreciated.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Peloton: Connecting experts with subscribers to drive engagement and loyalty&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The health and wellness company has harnessed the power of the subscription economy, combining connected exercise equipment with digital subscriptions to online fitness classes. Now, as Peloton re-adjusts to competing with gyms after its pandemic-era popularity, its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnbc.com/2021/10/07/how-peloton-builds-a-community-around-health-and-wellness.html&quot;&gt;community of almost 900,000 digital subscribers&lt;/a&gt; should stand it in good stead.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;One of its community-building tactics, in particular, should be of interest to publishers. Peloton’s fitness instructors have been instrumental in building connections with users — to the point where they’ve &lt;a href=&quot;https://connectthewatts.com/2021/06/15/inside-the-hollywoodization-of-peloton/&quot;&gt;become celebrities in their own right&lt;/a&gt;, increasing their pull still further. Similarly, publishers can &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/reader-comments-as-content-heres-why-it-works-for-aol-uk&quot;&gt;forge connections between editors and readers&lt;/a&gt;, ensuring high-quality conversations that increase “stickiness”.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Giffgaff: Community-based customer service drives engagement and lowers costs&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The UK mobile operator turned the cellular market on its head in 2009 by introducing a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.giffgaff.com/payback&quot;&gt;community-based customer service model&lt;/a&gt;. Rather than running a contact center, Giffgaff incentivizes its subscribers to answer other subscribers’ questions in its online community, in return for points that can be exchanged for cash, phone credits, or a charity donation.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The model has proven to be a huge win for the company and its subscribers alike — creating an online community of loyal users while minimizing service costs for Giffgaff. For publishers, it shows that creating dedicated spaces (such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/blog/how-publishers-can-attain-credibility-of-content/&quot;&gt;parenting forums&lt;/a&gt;), where subscribers can help each other out, can build community while keeping overheads down.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Salesforce: Making the community a visible and enticing part of the brand&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The cloud CRM software company is aimed at enterprises, but its fun, community-focused vibe is anything but corporate. Salesforce generates buzz and loyalty by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.salesforce.com/blog/so-what-is-a-trailblazer/&quot;&gt;elevating its “Trailblazers”&lt;/a&gt; — people who’ve achieved great things using its software — and turning them into highly visible ambassadors for the brand.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Salesforce Trailblazers are celebrated at company events, showered with merch, and showcased in TV ads. Day to day, they meet, chat and help each other out in the online community. The takeaway for publishers? Making readers part of your brand can be a recipe for long-term loyalty and engagement.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;Lego: Sourcing ideas from an engaged community of master builders&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Lego has always been about sparking the imagination of its users — whether they’re kids or AFOLs (that’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brickfanatics.com/lego-exclusive-afols-taught-us-to-take-adults-seriously/&quot;&gt;adult fans of Lego&lt;/a&gt;, for the non-initiated). So it&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://ideas.lego.com/howitworks&quot;&gt;Lego Ideas community&lt;/a&gt;, where fans can enter contests, show off their builds, and vote on others’ ideas, is core to what the brand stands for.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;But the community isn’t just a nice place to hang out — it’s also a source of ideas for new products. The Beatles’ Yellow Submarine, NASA’s Saturn V rocket, and the Ghostbusters ECTO-1 car are all genuine &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.denofgeek.com/culture/15-lego-sets-that-started-as-lego-ideas/&quot;&gt;Lego sets that started out as community-submitted ideas&lt;/a&gt;. Publishers can take a leaf out of Lego’s book and source editorial ideas from readers, too.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2 class=&quot;has-30-18-font-size&quot;&gt;It all starts by creating a space for conversation&lt;/h2&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The first step towards building an online community is to create a space that promotes quality conversations. Over 1,000 publishers are already doing that with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/openwebos/identity/&quot;&gt;OpenWebOS&lt;/a&gt;, a multi-layered moderation platform that enables high-quality, brand-safe interactions between publishers and readers, and between readers with each other.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been inspired by the brands we’ve highlighted above, find out more about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.openweb.com/openwebos/identity/&quot;&gt;turning casual readers into engaged community members with OpenWeb&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>